<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorials on Reggie Alderson</title>
    <link>https://reggiealderson.github.io/portfolio/categories/tutorials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorials on Reggie Alderson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://reggiealderson.github.io/portfolio/categories/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Finger on the property pulse - Part One</title>
      <link>https://reggiealderson.github.io/portfolio/blog/201001proj/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reggiealderson.github.io/portfolio/blog/201001proj/</guid>
      <description>This blog post documents the first stage of a data science project I have undertaken involving the application of New South Wales (NSW) residential property sales data.
In this first stage of the project, I have built a program using Python which automates the extraction, transformation, and storage of multiple years’ worth of New South Wales (NSW) property sales transactions.
The processed dataset is stored within an SQL database and is linked to a Power BI dashboard which visually portrays the best and worst performing real estate locations in the state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a rich dataset using web scraping with Python</title>
      <link>https://reggiealderson.github.io/portfolio/blog/200714proj/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reggiealderson.github.io/portfolio/blog/200714proj/</guid>
      <description>In this video tutorial I demonstrate how to create a sports statistics database using the simple, yet powerful data extraction technique known as web scraping. This technique involves collecting data across multiple web pages without having to open a web browser.
Tutorial:   Code used: # How to efficiently create a comprehensive sports statistics data set using web scraping and Python# Install the following python modules#1 pip install urllib3#2 pip install bs4#3 pip install regex#4 pip install pandasfrom urllib.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>